SHANE BUTLER

JUNIOR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

CONTACT

804 - 519 - 6013

shanedbutler@gmail.com

github.com/shanedbutler

linkedin.com/in/shanedbutler

EDUCATION

NewForce Coding School

June 2022 - January 2023 Fulltime Web Development Training

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

AZ-900 Certification - December 2022

Old Dominion University

August 2005 - January 2010 BFA - Photo and Print Media

PROJECTS

PUG Planner

Javascript / React / C# / SQL Server PUG Planner (Pick Up Game Planner) is a web-based application to plan, track, and manage community game events. PUG Planner manages a roster, wait-list, and notification system for each game event.

The application was created as a final full-stack capstone project to the NewForce coding school for use by a Los Angeles based community group.

What's for Dinner Poker

JavaScript / React / Bulma / SCSS Web-based game that is played to create a five-day meal plan. Users can choose to play from seasonal decks and save their game history for later reference.

The application was created as a midterm front-end capstone project to the NewForce coding school.

PROFILE

I am a full-stack developer who has shifted into tech from a 12-year career in photography. As a student of NewForce I've collaborated in teams using version control (Git), building front-end SPAs (Javascript / React), and writing back-end services (C# / .NET). I have a passion for web applications, learning, and utilizing my skills to reach creative solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Full-Stack Developer

June 2022 - Present

NewForce - Remote / Martinsburg, WV

- Applied object-oriented programming fundamentals through team based projects that reflect real world business problems.
- Collaborated remotely on projects using Slack and Zoom.
- Managed source code version control with Git and GitHub.
- Applied JavaScript, HTML, and CSS fundamentals to build a feature rich social media dashboard with CRUD functionality.
- Leveraged native ES6 module bundling to build DRY, reusable components.
- Designed and built capstone project "What's for Dinner Poker" with React using function component hooks, and Bulma CSS framework.
- Planned applications through white boarding dependencies, building ERDs, and sketching-up wireframes with Figma and FigJam.
- Built and interacted with databases using SQL Server and ADO.NET.
- Developed a blog management platform in ASP.NET with MVC.
- Developed full-stack application PUG Planner for Los Angeles client using RESTful Web API with C#/.NET Core, and connected to React SPA.
- Built and maintained unit tests in .NET Web APIs.

Professional Photographer

2010 - 2022

Freelance - Washington, D.C., Richmond, VA, and Durham, NC

Architectural photographer with additional experience in portraiture, art museum photography, and commercial videography. Remotely worked with Apartments.com and Google "Business View".

- Worked extensively with imaging and related software for client review, editing, post-production, and export.
- Deployed and manage workspace server for project tracking, delivery, invoicing, licensing, and asset archival.
- Designed and managed portfolio website using HTML and CSS.
- Maintain regular clients through marketing, on-time delivery, clear communication, and persistent attention to detail and client needs.
- Planned and led after-school class for children on basics of photography.